Benjamin Banwart

Fort Scott, Kansas

Benjibanwart@gmail.com | (620)404-2094 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio Site

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in full-stack web development including front-end, back-end, database, and testing. Currently working for Miller's Professional Imaging as a full-time Software Engineer. Attended a 9 month full-stack software engineering certificate program with Kansas State University. Most efficient when working and collaborating with others. Much of my class and project time at Kansas State University was spent as a team lead where I began to develop leadership attributes. Avid lifetime learner and passionate about automation of repetitive tasks, providing meaningful solutions to businesses, and exceptional visual design.

EDUCATION

Kansas State University

Manhattan, KS

Full Stack Software Development Professional Certificate

July 2022

Courses: Front-End Development, UI-UX, Back-End Development and APIs, React-Redux, SQL and Data Modeling, MERN-stack Project, Principles of Programming in Python, Advanced Programming Topics

SKILLS PROFILE

Certification: Software Engineer

Development Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Flask, CSS, SASS, SCSS, HTML, AWS, VS Code, Visual Studio, GitHub, PgAdmin, C#, .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET, Razor Pages, PSQL, Sequelize, JQuery, Postman, Trello, APIs, Jinja, Git, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap, Mongoose, Axios, macOS, Linux, Windows, aws4

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

Deployment Tools: GitHub Pages, Heroku, Netlify, ElephantSQL, MongoDB Atlas, Amazon S3 Bucket, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, CircleCI, Microsoft Azure Web App

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

MERNstagram May 2022

• Engineered a full scale PERN-stack application as team lead with three other classmates at K-State for a group milestone project.

- Create, view, edit, and delete social media posts in this application like you would with similar social media apps.
- App is hosted in three places: the client is hosted on Netlify, the server is hosted on Heroku, and the Database is hosted with ElephantSQL.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Material-UI, PostgreSQL, React, Git, ElephantSQL, PgAdmin, Axios, Express, NodeJS, and JSX.
- This project was instrumental in showing all of the group how to function as a team, develop in a real-world development environment, and properly use all of the different version control features of git and github.

CodeDeets July 2022

• Lead a team of developers at KSU in making an online forum for developers to collaborate on ideas, make tutorials, and provide informative posts on how to solve problems.

- Application is full scale with the following features: user accounts, admin roles, CRUD functionality with posts, front end, back end, database.
- Users submit markdown (.md) files as their user content and can browse all posts on the main page.
- App is hosted with AWS Elastic Beanstalk and ElephantSQL.
- Development technologies include: JavaScript, React, Material-UI, PostgreSQL, Axios, Express, NodeJS, and Multer.

REST-Rant March 2022

- Engineered a full-stack application that allows users to review restaurants while admin roles have privileges to add restaurants, remove users, and remove reviews.
- Implemented user authentication with roles.
- The app is hosted on Heroku and uses MongoDB as a database.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, JSX, and express-react-views.

Pokemon_Battle_Game

January 2022–February 2022

- Developed a fully-functional Pokémon battle game that runs in the browser using raw HTML, CSS, and JavaScript as a solo milestone project for K-State.
- The JavaScript logic allows for a user to choose his or her party of Pokémon and then battle against a computer player and its Pokémon until the user wins or loses.
- Project consists of large amounts of JavaScript logic, HTML objects, CSS styling, and sprites.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Miller's Professional Imaging, Pittsburg, KS

June 2023-Present

Software Engineer

- Built application to gather key production data and send it out in automated emails
- Develop business aiding features on already existing projects
- Critical bug fixes in large collection of repositories
- Develop systems based off of a highly complex product system
- Build and manage projects from ground to deployment
- Constant agile development collaboration with team of engineers

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

August 2022–June 2023

Software Developer

- Write Jinja templates in ERP system
- Advise web design
- UI/UX
- Continue with previous responsibilities

Sekan Printing, Fort Scott, KS

July 2022–June 2023

Software Developer Contract

- Develop task automation web applications for product creation on multiple sales channels
- Working with third party APIs and creating local API infrastructure
- Created a front end/back end web app as a portal for Sekan to view, use, and manage software
- Setup Microsoft Azure for company
- Developed web scraper to aid in repetitive tasks while purchasing supplies
- Created data collection web application

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

February 2020–August 2022

Catalog Listing Assistant

- List highly detailed and niche products on Amazon, Etsy, Walmart
- Communicate regularly with the product analyst and the sales department in creating the varying products with details that are oriented for sales optimization
- Fix broken listings and update prices to increase profit margins

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

April 2014-February 2020

Warehouse Laborer

- Worked in product production and conversion
- Converted large product units to multiple smaller product units while operating a machine
- Kept shelves saturated with products for pickers
- Troubleshoot inventory errors using an online SKU-based inventory management system and communication with co-workers